本期教程中我们将展示如何
In this lesson we're going to show how to
导入给定的粒子样例素材
take the content examples that are given specifically the particle example
并将其加入已有项目
and maybe add it to a project that basically already exist.
然后在场景中查看这些粒子
So then we can take the particles and we can view them in the scene.
我已经下载好了GameSDK样例项目
So to get started, I've already download the Game SDK sample project that shown right here,
这里显示已经下好了
and it shows that it's installed.
首先要做的是 进入这个项目的目录
So the first thing we need to do is actually target this project at where it resides.
在文件资源管理器中打开
So we're gonna reveal in the explorer, if I bring that up, we can see
可以看见这个项目存储在C盘
that this project actually resides in the C root
CRYENGINE Launcher\Crytek\GameSDK_5.0
而这个文件夹就是真正的游戏文件夹
and then this is your actual game folder.
要添加现有的项目
So to take a previous to project,
我们要做的是 返回
what we're gonna do is step back,
然后 我们点击Add Existing
and we're going to click Add Existing project.
点击后 会弹出窗口
Once we click this, we'll get a little prompt
在这里可以选择项目文件夹
and it allows us to browse for the folder.
我们曾说过 GameSDK位于C盘
If you remember we said that it was in the C root,
进入C:\CRYENGINE Launcher\Crytek\ 可以看到GameSDK_5.0
so if we go in here, we can see that we have CRYENGINE Launcher\Crytek\GameSDK_5.0,
里面的GameSDK便是我们想要的
and then GameSDK is what we want to target.
点击OK 我们就导入了已有的项目
We're gonna click OK, and now we have added an existing project, it's all new.
假如说 我想添加关卡到已有项目 例如 添加到样例项目
But say we wanna add another level to an existing project that we got, say in the sample project.
要想做到这点
So, to do that,
我们先把这个关掉
let's go ahead and close this,
我们进入GameSDK这个文件夹
and we're gonna target the GameSDK project specifically in this path,
再打开SAMPLE_CONTENT
open the SAMPLE_CONTENT,
再进入到CONTENT_EXAMPLES\GameSDK
if we go to CONTENT_EXAMPLES\GameSDK,
可以看见这里有个Assets文件夹
we can see that we have Assets,
里面有Particles和Levels文件夹
and then we have Particles and we have Levels.
我们先进到Assets 因为我不想都复制到上一级
So let's go inside of here, because I don't wanna load up everything,
我们拖住contentExample
and I'm gonna grab the contentExample
拖到levels里
and drag that in,
然后拖住Particles到这里
and I'm gonna take the particles and drag that in.
现在一切都准备好了 我们可以打开启动器了
So now we're ready to fire up the launcher, because we've put everything into our project.
点击这里
If we just click here,
引擎便打开了
now we have the engine open, and click down here.
不过我好像点了两下
Since it's ready, I also I think I click twice,
那个窗口取消就行 打开多个引擎也没有关系
so we can remove that, doesn't matter if you open another instance thought.
打开File->Open->contentExample
To File->Open->contentExample,
我们好好看看PARTICLE_CONTENT_EXAMPLE
we're gonna look specifically for the PARTICLE_CONTENT_EXAMPLE.
我们双击它
So if I double click this,
引擎便会加载关卡
it'll load the file with the level.
加载后 可以看到所有粒子都排列在这里 准备使用
And then when it happened, we can see that we have all of the particles lined up to be ready to be used,
它们都有名称 我们有3D旋转 体积 都在这个关卡里
and they all have a name, say 3d rotation, volume, and pretty much, you can go and explore these
with the PARTICLE_CONTENT_EXAMPLE. To access the actual particle editor,
要访问粒子编辑器
可以打开Tools->Particle Editor
you wanna go to Tools->Particle Editor,
它会在这里加载所有粒子
and it will automatically load the particles over here.
你可以选择任何一个 例如 3D旋转
And you can choose anything, like 3d rotation,
拖住编辑器标题栏
just right here, and hit this for a second,
拖到这里 可以合并窗口
move that over there,
往上拉 拉远点
bring this up, scroll up a little bit,
可以看见 这张节点图 能让3D旋转效果运作
and we can see this is the actual chain, it allows for the 3d rotation to work.
把这个往上拉一点
Bring it up a little closer,
现在 可以看见粒子在编辑器里的样子
and now we can see exactly what it looks like in the editor,
以及在图像编辑器里的样子
we can see what it looks like in the graphic editor for the particles.
希望你能阅览这个项目
And I hope you can explore this projects and
并在开发中使用到这些粒子
get them up and running for your own development, because
因为 DX12版的新粒子效果相较于旧版粒子系统有很大提升
particle effects 2 for our DX12 branch has been a great boost compare to the old particle system,
我想大家都会喜欢这个新粒子系统
and I think everybody's gonna like it.
翻译：他出院了